JON WRIGHT

Web Developer

(540) 330-5231 jonwright.va@gmail.com www.jonwright.io Washington, DC

SKILLS

- Adobe Creative Suite
- AngularJS
- CSS
- Git
- HTML
- JavaScript
- iQuery
- MongoDB
- Node
- PostgreSQL
- React
- Redux
- Ruby on Rails
- Sketch
- Vue.js

With a background in environmental science and sustainability, I always welcome opportunities to apply my experience to overcome challenging problems. As a believer that the details hold everything together, I'm driven by thoughtful and creative problem-solving to make successful impacts on larger levels.

RELEVANT EXPERIENCE

General Assembly: Web Development Immersive Student

March 2017 - June 2017

Completed a 3-month Web Development Intensive. During this intensive, I learned a variety of web methodologies and frameworks. With projects used to capstone that knowledge. Creating a portfolio of projects including:

- Reci.by Built using Ruby on Rails, Reci.by is a CRUD web application using ERB for the views, and deployed using Heroku
- Freekend This app uses a Rails backend and AngularJS on the frontend. Using API calls, Freekend finds local events and allow users to comment on them
- Eventer This MERN (Mongo, Express, React, Node) app created as a prototype for the Drop-In Center, a public health nonprofit. Using the Mapbox API with Leaflet, local events are saved and displayed on a map

EDUCATION

General Assembly: WDI

June 2017

B.S., Environmental Studies,

Cum Laude

Roanoke College December 2013

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Press Press Merch: Shipping Manager

April 2016 - March 2017

- Communicated production variances to management
- Ensured product quality and customer satisfaction
- Prepared shipments for postal or commercial conveyance

VOLUNTEER EXPERIENCE

Blue Ridge Literacy Center

Worked pro-bono as a photographer

Code For DC

Volunteered with the DC Abortion Fund

Gridpoint: Commissioner

December 2013 - April 2016

- Commissioned the most sites for two years in a row
- Developed extensive knowledge of product platforms to resolve product failures
- Analyzed data and trends to provide customer support and troubleshoot products
- · Advised product design reviews for quality control and reliability input
- Supervised troubleshooting and corrective action activities
- Collected and displayed data in a logical manner
- Taught and mentored other support and field service personnel